The destructive impact of fast fashion on the environment is widely documented.
快时尚对环境造成的破坏性影响已被大量研究证实。
So how can we, as consumers, reduce our fashion footprint?
那么，作为消费者，我们该如何减少自己的时尚碳足迹呢？
One obvious answer is to buy less.
一个显而易见的办法是减少购买量。
Another is to buy clothes that have been more sustainably made, using organic and recycled materials.
另一个办法是选购采用有机及再生材料制作、更具可持续性的服装。
Hiring clothes is another way to get new pieces for our wardrobe.
租衣服也是为衣橱添置新品的一种方式。
But buying second-hand may be the simplest solution and a trend that is growing fast.
但购买二手衣物或许是最简单的解决方案，同时这也是一个正在迅速兴起的趋势。
According to the Boston Consulting Group, second-hand clothes are projected to make up 27 per cent of customers’ wardrobes by 2023.
波士顿咨询集团的数据显示，到2023年，二手衣物预计将占到消费者衣橱衣物总量的27%。
By 2030, the second-hand clothing market is projected to be twice the size of fast fashion, according to a global report by Thredup and GlobalData.
二手寄售平台Thredup与市场研究机构GlobalData联合发布的一份全球报告指出，到2030年，二手服装市场的规模预计将达到快时尚市场的两倍。
So, it seems, the next ten years will see the resale market grow fast, and this is in part because we now have more options than simply buying from charity shops and jumble sales. Online sites are making it easier to both buy and sell pre-loved items.
由此可见，貌似未来十年二手转售市场将迎来快速增长，部分原因在于，如今人们购买二手衣物的渠道不再局限于慈善商店和旧货义卖活动，各类线上平台让二手物品的买卖变得愈发便捷。
It also helps that the perception of pre-loved clothing has changed.
公众对二手衣物的看法转变也推动了这一趋势的发展。
Dr Amna Khan, senior lecturer in consumer behaviours and retail at Manchester Metropolitan University, said ‘it’s now become trendy to wear second-hand’ and it’s no longer ‘a case of only buying it if you can’t afford anything else’.
曼彻斯特城市大学消费者行为与零售业高级讲师阿姆娜·汗博士表示，“如今穿二手衣已经成了一种潮流”，而不再是“只有买不起新衣服才会去买的无奈之选”。
The changing values of shoppers is even being seen in celebrity culture, with television personalities, such as contestants on the popular UK TV show Love Island, promoting second-hand clothing.
消费者的价值观转变甚至在名人文化中也有所体现，英国热门电视节目《爱情岛》的选手等电视名人都在为二手服装代言宣传。
Not everyone is convinced that these changes in shopping habits will do enough to reduce our fashion footprint.
不过，并非所有人都认为购物习惯的这些转变足以减少我们的时尚碳足迹。
The charity Wrap tells people to repair and revamp clothes they already have in their wardrobe before buying new ones, even if they are second-hand.
慈善机构WRAP建议人们，在购买新衣服（即便是二手衣物）之前，先对衣橱里现有的衣服进行修补和翻新。
But it’s clear that some consumers now want to consume less and make more environmentally friendly choices when they do buy.
但显而易见的是，如今部分消费者希望减少消费，并且在不得不购买时做出更环保的选择。
The fashion industry is therefore having to change, and the second-hand market is the star of the show.
时尚行业因此不得不做出改变，而二手市场则成了这场变革中的主角。